Zeeshan Hanif

Professional Summary

Experienced developer with over six years of personal experience and two years of industry experience. Has led all stages of development, including design, implementation, testing, and maintenance. Experienced in working with large codebases in an Agile environment.

Education

University of California, Irvine

September 2015 - December 2018

B.Sc. Computer Science (specializing in Systems and Software)

Technical Proficiencies

Languages: C++, Java, Javascript, Python, SQL

Skills: Agile, API Development, Cloud Infrastructure, Database Administration, System & Performance Testing

Recent Experience

Software Engineer (Google - Seattle, WA)

July 2019 - Present

- Developing world class APIs and great user experiences on a simple, efficient stack.
- Keeping the Google Cloud Storage JSON API up and running; my work involving global failure mitigation ensures our platforms can quickly, correctly, and reliably handle the millions of QPS our customers send us everyday.

Software Engineer (Alcatel-Lucent Enterprise - Calabasas, CA)

October 2017 - June 2018

- My internship was extended, and I began working remotely as a part-time engineer while attending school. The majority of my time was spent continuing work on my intern project. I had another project, briefly described below.
- Worked on refreshing the decade-old web interface of our network switches. This required me to work with engineers from Southern California and France to produce a requirements document.
- Refactored a subset of UI components specific to the VLAN config view, focusing on modularity and code health.

Engineering Intern (Alcatel-Lucent Enterprise - Calabasas, CA)

July 2017 - September 2017

- Developed a ticketing platform focused on logging project progress. The goal of the platform was to allow multiple employees to function more efficiently when dealing with bugs.
- Worked with a legacy PHP backend and a JavaScript frontend, focused on providing employees with a responsive application to manage their tickets.
- Implemented a dashboard overview of tickets, import and export of tickets to Excel, and a notification system.
- Added monitoring resources and UI elements to the dashboard, import and export functionality to and from Excel, and a basic notification system.

Recent Projects

Cinematcha (Javascript, PHP, MySQL)

January 2018 - March 2018

- Built a movie recommendation engine on top of TheMovieDB, as a research project in search systems.
- Researched algorithmic models for dynamic recommendation engines.
- Increased and decreased the ranking of a recommendation based on a variety of weighted factors (e.g. watch history, favorite genre, favorite films of users with similar tastes, the weather, the time of day, etc.).

Roboto or Notto (Mathematica, React)

March 2017

- Created a game in which the user must decide if their opponent is a chatbot or not by the end of a 30 second round.
- Generated chatbots from pools of conversations mined from online forums.
- Used English structural language analysis to select appropriate responses from a Markov Chain of possibilities.